GUY ALLON

Data Analyst | Data Scientist | Biologist

I am a Bio-scientist with a passion for data and data-driven insights, seeking an entry-level position as a Data Analyst or a Data Scientist, utilizing my data analysis, programming, and complex problem-solving skills.

9 years as an R&D scientist have taught me that critical thinking, fast learning, and adaptability are much-needed skills when tackling a new problem. I'm ready to apply these skills, along with recently taught Python and SQL data analysis skills to any new challenge.

See my Data Analytics Portfolio:

https://guyallon.github.io/GuyDataAnalytics.github.io/

EXPERIENCE

Nes-Ziona, IL Jul 2021 - Jun 2023

Scientist

A2i-Therapeutics

- · Cancer biology and drug discovery
- Assay development
- Data analysis

Rehovot, IL Apr 2019 - Mar 2020

Synthetic Biologist

Wild Biotech

• R&D - synthetic biology

Rehovot, IL Mar 2017 - Apr 2019

Lead Researcher and Project manager

CTG-Pharma

- Led key R&D projects in immunotherapy, in charge of team management
- Developed rapid and low-cost DNA assembly and cloning pipelines that significantly advanced R&D activity
- · Participated in patent writing

EDUCATION

San Francisco, CA Sep 2021 - Aug 2022

Certificate, Data Scientist in Python

Dataquest.io

- Data cleaning, analysis, and visualization (Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn, Matplotlib)
- Implementing common machine learning (ML) algorithms (Regressions, decision trees, KNNs, K-means, random forests, etc.)
- Jupyter Notebook, Anaconda, VScode, Power BI, excel
- SQL queries, SQLite, Postgress

Oct 2013 - Mar 2016

M.Sc. Life Sciences

Ben Gurion University

Thesis: From a molecular mechanism to improved protein utilization and growth of gilthead sea bream. Patent: COMPOSITIONS AND METHODS FOR AQUACULTURE.

Oct 2010 - Aug 2013

B.Sc. Life Sciences

Ben Gurion University

- Awards for excellence in a research project
- Presentation at Epigenetics for Improved Food Production, Oct.2013, Spain

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Intro to Data Analysis in Microsoft Power BI, Dataquest.io, Jan 2023 PostgresSQL for Data Engineering, Dataquest.io, Dec 2022 Intermediate SQL for Data Engineering, Dataquest.io, Nov 2022 APIs and Web Scraping with Python, Dataquest.io, Oct 2022 Data Analysis for Business in Python Course, Dataquest.io, Dec 2021

PUBLICATIONS

- Allon, G., Gaon, A., Nixon, O., Bitan, A., Tandler, A., & Koven, W. (2016). A novel approach to introduce nutrients into the fish egg; the effect of egg taurine on first feeding gilthead sea bream (Sparus aurata) performance. Aquaculture, 451, 9398.
- Others: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aquaculture.2017.09.039; https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aquaculture.2017.11.011; https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cbpa.2018.11.005.

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email

guyallon2@gmail.com

Phone

+972547451152

Link

linkedin.com/in/guy-allon

SKILLS

- Data Science (Python)
- Machine learning (basic)
- R&D Mindset
- SQL | mySQL | SQLite
- Power BI | Tableau
- Teamwork
- Written communication
- Critical thinking
- Adaptability

LANGUAGES

Hebrew

Native

English

Advanced